# **WONHO BAE**

☐ github.com/won-bae ☑ whbae@cs.ubc.ca � won-bae.github.io � linkedin.com/in/wonho-bae ♥ Vancouver, BC ७ +1-604-396-7539

Research enthusiast interested in machine learning and computer vision, specifically for low supervision regime such as **self and weakly supervised** as well as **active and meta learning** in the **object recognition** framework.

### **EDUCATION**

University of British Columbia PhD of Computer Science	Sep 2020 - Present GPA: 4.00
University of Massachusetts, Amherst	Sep 2018 - May 2020
Master of Computer Science	GPA: 3.78
University of California, Berkeley Bachelor of Statistics	Sep 2013 - Dec 2017 GPA: 3.76
Santa Monica College	Sep 2011 - May 2013
Associate of Economics, member of Alpha Gamma Sigma	GPA: 3.95

### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### **Borealis AI at Vancouver**

*May* 2022 - *Sep* 2022

Research Intern

- Supervisor: Dr. Gabriel Oliveira, Dr. Fred Tung, and Dr. Mohamed Ahmed
- Conducted a research on temporal point processes to capture periodic patterns in long-term event sequences.

# Vision & Learning Lab at Seoul National University

Feb 2018 - Sep 2020

Research Assistant

- Supervisor: Prof. Gunhee Kim
- Conducted a research on i) small object detection using Generative Adversarial Network in Faster R-CNN framework, ii) object localization task under weakly-supervised learning setting using a class activation mapping method.

## Data Science for Common Good Fellowship at UMass, Amherst

May 2019 - Aug 2019

Research Fellow

- Supervisor: Dr. Brant Cheikes, Prof. Matthew Rattigan
- Conducted a research on classifying wild animal images collected using camera traps in collaboration with The Nature Conservancy. Deployed a web-based open-source tool for ecologists.

### Renewable & Appropriate Energy Lab at UC Berkeley

Jan 2017 - Dec 2017

Research Assistant

- Supervisor: Prof. Daniel Kammen, Prof. Deborah Sunter
- Participated in the Inclusive Green Growth porject. Worked on keyword detection task using Natural Language Process techniques to replace synonyms and pronouns in the text. Currently writing a book to publish.

### **PUBLICATIONS**

- [1] Wonho Bae, Mohamed Osama Ahmed, Gabriel Leivas Oliveira, Frederick Tung, "Meta Temporal Point Processes", **Under Review**.
- [2] Mohamad Amin Mohamadi\*, **Wonho Bae**\*, Danica Sutherland, "Making Look-Ahead Active Learning Strategies Feasible with Neural Tangent Kernels", in **NeurIPS 2022**, New Orleans, LA, Nov 2022.
- [3] Jinhwan Seo, **Wonho Bae**, Danica Sutherland, Junhyug Noh, Daijin Kim "Object Discovery via Contrastive Learning for Weakly Supervised Object Detection", in **ECCV 2022**, Tel-Aviv, Israel, Oct 2022.
- [4] **Wonho Bae**, Junhyug Noh, Milad Jalali Asadabadi, Danica J. Sutherland, "One Weird Trick to Improve Your Semi-Weakly Supervised Semantic Segmentation Model", in **IJCAI 2022**, Vienna, Austria, July 2022.

- [5] Wonho Bae\*, Junhyug Noh\*, Gunhee Kim, "Rethinking Class Activations Mapping for Weakly Supervised Object Localization", in ECCV 2020, online, Aug 2020.
- [6] **Wonho Bae\***, Junhyug Noh\*, Gunhee Kim, "Revisiting Class Activations Mapping for Learning from Imperfect Data", in **CVPRW 2020**, online, June 2020.
- [7] Junhyug Noh, Kyung Don Yoo, **Wonho Bae**, ..., YonSu Kim, Gunhee Kim, "Prediction of the Mortality Risk in Peritoneal Dialysis Patients using Machine Learning Models: A Nation-wide Prospective Cohort in Korea", in **Scientific Reports** (2020) by Nature Publishing Group.
- [8] Junhyug Noh, Wonho Bae, Wonhee Lee, Jinhwan Seo and Gunhee Kim, "Better to Follow, Follow to Be Better: Towards Precise Supervision of Feature Super-Resolution for Small Object Detection", in ICCV 2019, Seoul, Korea, Oct 2019.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Republic of Korea Army

Feb 2015 - Nov 2016

Signals Intelligence Analyst

- Served in the intelligence battalion of the Republic of Korea Army for 21 months as a signals intelligence analyst.

### AWARD & SCHOLARSHIP

# **Learning from Imperfect Data (LID) Competition - 1st**

June 2020

1st place in LID workshop at CVPR 2020

# **Data Science for Common Good Fellowship**

May 2019 - Aug 2019

Research fellow in the Center of Data Science at UMass, Amherst

### **American Math Competitions**

2011 - 2012

3rd place in 2011 and 1st place in 2012

#### **TEACHING**

### **Teaching Assistant**

Computer Vision (CPSC 425 - UBC, Vancouver)

Fall 2021, 2022

Grader

Computer Vision (COMPSCI 670 - UMass, Amherst)

Fall 2019

### **OUTREACH/PRESENTATIONS**

### Talk at ViewMagine (Online)

Jan 2021

Gave a talk about 'how to access a research problem in computer vision' based on the publications from ICCV 2019 and ECCV 2020 and research design course in UMass.

### AI Summer Seminar at UMass, Amherst

Summer 2019

Hosted AI seminar at UMass during Summer of 2019. Discussed various topics related to AI including but not limited to computer vision, natural language process and planning.

### Presentation for Inclusive Green Growth at Institute of Advanced Study, Germany

Aug 2018

Gave a talk about a data-driven approach for measuring Inclusive Green Growth of different countries and regions at Hanse-Wissenschaftskolleg Institute for Advanced Study in Germany.

### **SERVICES**

### **Paper Review**

NeurIPS (2021, 2022), CVPR (2022), ICML (2022)

Volunteer Sep 2022 - Dec 2022

Mentor in Science Undergraduate Society Mentorship Program at UBC